翻譯：冰藍 珞珞 MythCreator 小泓泓 衛老哥 魚小姐啦 小雷_Amber
時間軸：MH 冰藍 擱淺   后期：MythCreator
校對：Michael 圈圈  青椒  總監:  蘋果果
我的名字叫奧利弗·奎恩
My name is Oliver Queen.
五年里  我被困在地獄一般的小島上
After five years on a hellish island,
我回來只有一個目標
I have come home with only one goal--
拯救我的城市
to save my city.
但要達到目標  我不能像過去一樣成為兇手
But to do so, I can't be the killer I once was.
為了紀念我的朋友
To honor my friend's memory,
我只能偽裝成另一個人
I must be someone else.
深切懷念托馬斯·梅林
孝子
成為另一個存在
I must be something else.
《綠箭》前情回顧
Previously on "Arrow"...
這個人對我們沒用了
This one's no longer of use to us.
等一下  他或許還有用
Wait. He could still be useful.
她說得對  一旦我們殺了他的朋友
She's right. Once we get rid of his friends,
我們就得需要他帶我們去墓地了
we'll need him to lead us to the grave.
你要再回到島上
You're going back to the island.
你已經失去你的父親了
Look, you already lost your dad.
你母親還在
Your mom, she's still here.
她一定很想見見你
And I'm sure she'd love to see you.
我不會去監獄看她
I'm not going to that prison.
我只知道這樣才能讓她痛苦
It's the only way I know how to hurt her.
我很想恨你
And I want to hate you.
但是我恨不起來
But I can't.
我一直以為我們之間沒有秘密
I didn't think that there were secrets kept between us.
媽媽  你在隱瞞什么
Mom...what are you hiding?
我是莫伊拉·迪爾登·奎恩
My name is Moira Dearden Queen.
我是奎恩聯合企業的代理執行總裁
I am the acting CEO of Queen Consolidated.
半年前
上帝  請原諒我  我辜負了這座城市
And, god forgive me, I have failed this city.
我被迫參與了一項事業
I have been complicit in an undertaking
它有一個恐怖的目的
with one horrible purpose--
摧毀貧民區以及里面每一個人
to destroy the glades and everyone in it.
如果你住在貧民區
If you reside in the glades,
貧民區遭到攻擊
請立刻離開
please, you need to get out now.
你和你的孩子們  命懸一線
Your lives and the lives of your children depend on it.
拜托了
Please.
典獄長說我們得撤退了
Warden says we got to evacuate.
幫我拿走這些
Help me get these out of here.
-那囚犯呢  -不管他們
- What about the inmates? - Leave 'em.
-來  放我出去  -不
- Over here, let me out. - No.
-把鑰匙給我  -不不  你太暴力
- Give me the keys! - No, no, too violent.
-帶我走  -太邋遢  太愚蠢
- Take me! - Too sloppy, too stupid.
你太野心勃勃
Too...ambitious.
你
You.
我喜歡你的工作
I love your work.
很有前途
Big future.
小心點
Hey, be careful.
可能會有余震
There's liable to be aftershocks.
我巴不得呢
Oh, I'm counting on it.
綠箭  第二季第七集
現在
奎恩先生  您母親勝訴的幾率有多大
Mr. Queen, what are your mother's chances?
是不是有人監視以防她自殺
Is she on suicide watch?
奎恩先生  能發表評論嗎
Mr. Queen, can you give us any comment?
這不公平  又不是他們進行庭審
It's not fair. They're not the ones on trial.
那也不能阻止簡·洛林
That won't stop Jean Loring
用他們來獲取公眾的同情
from using them as props to drum up sympathy.
你看起來不大擔心
You don't seem overly concerned.
她在直播電視里承認自己是共犯
She confessed to being an accomplice on live television.
她也說了是馬爾科姆·梅林強迫的她
She also sad that Malcolm Merlyn coerced her.
你有什么證據  對吧
You have something, don't you?
我是你的合伙律師  亞當
I thought I was your co-counsel, Adam.
如果你手里有王牌
If you're holding a trump card,
難道不該和我分享一下嗎
don't you think maybe you should share it with me?
這場庭審會很棒的
It's going to be a good trial.
我們進去吧
Come on, let's get inside.
你沒必要這樣做
You don't have to do this.
艾沃說有必要
Ivo says we do.
你的朋友們對他的人來說是個威脅
Your friends are a danger to his men.
快去  別驚動他們
Go. Quick and quiet.
斯萊德  莎朵  快跑
Slade! Shado! Run!
里面沒人
There's no one here.
他們肯定轉移了
They must have moved on from their position.
炸藥放好了  這是引爆器
Chargers are placed. Here's the detonator.
確保他們無"家"可歸
Make sure they have no place to return to.
去吧
Go.
你
And you.
現在你要帶我們去墓地
Now you're going to take us to the graves.
走吧  拉他起來
Let's go. Get him up.
動身
Let's get clear.
你找到引爆器了嗎
Did you find the detonator?
找到了
Yes.
我們真走運
We were lucky.
是我走運  你很厲害
I was lucky. You were good.
不管怎樣
Either way...
奧利弗都在他們手上
they have Oliver.
我去找他
I'm going after him.
我陪你去
Not alone.
你都沒法走路
You can barely walk.
所以我更不能待在這里
All the more reason not to stay here.
不能再給他們一次把我炸飛的機會
Give them another chance at blowing me up.
你倆沒事吧
Are you two ok?
我該問你這個問題
I should be asking you that question.
我沒事
I'll be fine.
你看上去像得了流感
You look like you have the flu.
如果真是那樣  我不該
If that's true, I shouldn't
浪費時間接種疫苗的
have wasted my time getting vaccinated.
狄格爾  不管是怎么回事  回家去吧
Diggle, whatever it is, just go home.
奧利弗  我能處理好的  好嗎
Oliver, listen, I can take care of things. All right?
不  我們沒事的
No, we'll be fine, all right?
去休息吧  別逼我叫警察
Go rest. And don't make me call a cop.
這里就有幾個
There are a few of them around here.
我被迫參與了一項事業
I have been complicit in an undertaking
它有一個恐怖的目的
with one horrible purpose--
摧毀貧民區以及里面每一個人
to destroy the glades and everyone in it.
奏效了  貧民區被毀
And it worked. The Glades were destroyed.
哀橫遍野  人們流離失所
Homes and lives were lost.
都是因為她的行為
All because of her actions.
確實  她想清楚之后做了悔改
True, she had second thoughts;
自責促使她發表這份聲明
remorse which compelled her to deliver this statement.
但我想替那天逝去的503條生命
But on behalf of the 503 lives
在這里說一句話
that were extinguished that day,
莫伊拉·奎恩  你的自責太遲了
I say, Moira Queen, your remorse comes too late.
在過去的五年里
For the last five years,
我和我家人的生命
under the threat for my life
受到了威脅
and the lives of my family...
為什么這些威脅沒有讓她沉默
Why wouldn't those threats silence her?
為什么莫伊拉·奎恩沒有被嚇倒
Why wouldn't Moira Queen be terrified?
馬爾科姆·梅林殺了她的第一任丈夫
Malcolm Merlyn killed her first husband,
綁架了她的第二任丈夫
abducted her second.
她為什么不擔心自己的性命
Why wouldn't she be in fear for her life?
不擔心自己兒女的性命
For the lives of her children?
你們會怎么做
What would you do?
如果你們的子女
If it were your children in the crosshairs
被一個瘋子控制
of a mad man's rage?
星級實驗室的粒子加速器
They say the Star lab's particle accelerator
會如期開啟
will be turned on right on schedule.
其他新聞  我們剛剛收到消息
In other news, we have just received word
莫伊拉·奎恩庭審中的正反兩方
that both sides have now completed their opening statements
都已經完成了開庭陳詞
in the Moira Queen trial.
別理解錯了  但你看起來很惡心
Don't take this the wrong way, but you look disgusting.
好吧  我感覺不太好  費利西蒂
Yeah, well, I don't feel great, Felicity.
你有沒有解決的辦法
Is there a right way to take that?
你應該回家
You should go home.
我正要回去
I am going.
我只是得安排一個替補保鏢
I just need to make arrangements for a replacement bodyguard.
你打流感疫苗了嗎  我從沒打過
Did you get the flu shot? Personally, I never do.
我知道我應該打
I know that I should.
可我  我對針頭很恐懼
I just, I have this thing about needles.
對尖的東西都恐懼
All pointy things, really.
這很諷刺  想想我們跟誰共事
Which is ironic, considering who we work with.
對  不是流感  費利西蒂  更像是
Yeah, it's not the flu, Felicity, it's more like...
狄格
Dig!
有人嗎
Hello?
你在這里嗎
Are you here?
在這里  在那里
Here...there...
在任何地方
Everywhere.
那么
So.
我們的科學項目進展如何
How goes our little science project?
如你所料
Working like you said it would.
多美妙啊
How wonderful.
是這樣
Ah, so listen.
干這事要五萬塊
Doing the thing was 50,000.
保守這個秘密
Keeping quiet about it,
我覺得應該再加五萬
I'm thinking it should be 50 more.
不過我想讓流言傳開
Oh, I want word to spread.
這正是整體目標的一部分
It's kind of the whole objective, actually.
你懂我意思嗎
You see my point?
你應該知道  我覺得事后談判
You should know, I find post hoc negotiation...
很令人討厭
distasteful.
真可惜你看不到你的工作
Such a shame you won't get to see
會得到怎樣的成果  博士
what your works have wrought, doctor.
但很快  所有人都能看到
But soon, everyone else will.
而且他們會祈求它快點結束
And they'll beg for it to end.
你來這里干什么
What the hell are you doing here?
我聽說你昏過去了
I heard you passed out.
我讓費利西蒂別打電話給你
I told Felicity not to call you.
對  但在那之前  你喊了一聲就倒下了
Yeah, but before that, you said "Gaw" And "Thud,"
所以我沒把你的話當回事
so I didn't take it very seriously.
她打給我是對的  狄格爾  你需要就醫
She was right to call me. Diggle, you need medical attention.
他不止需要就醫  狄格昏過去時
He needs more than that. When Dig passed out,
我把他的血樣給了公司里的一個化學家
I sent a sample of his blood to a chemist I know at QC.
他欠我人情  說來話長
The guy owes me a favor. Long story,
我幫他取消過停車罰單
I fixed his parking ticket.
其實也不是很長
Huh. I guess it's not that long.
費利西蒂  血樣
Felicity. The blood sample.
對  迷魂檢測的結果  顯示陽性
Yeah. It came back positive-- for trace amounts of Vertigo.
我從沒用過迷魂
I never used Vertigo before in my life.
你肯定是接觸到了
You were exposed to it somehow.
迷魂又出現了嗎
Vertigo's in play again?
伯爵迷魂吸入過量治好后
When the Count recovered from his OD on Vertigo,
他被送到了鐵山監獄
he was sent to Iron Heights.
監獄在地震中被毀
That got hit in the quake.
他和娃娃制造者是同一種方式出來的
He got out the same way the Doll Maker did?
而且和娃娃制造者一樣
And just like with the Doll Maker,
警方加班加點地工作來掩蓋他的逃逸
prison officials worked overtime to keep the lid on the escape.
-我知道你在想什么  -不  你不知道
- I know what you're thinking. - No, you don't.
我當時選擇不殺這個人
I made ahoice not to put an arrow in this guy.
而這么做是對的
And it was the right choice.
不會再有殺戮
There's no more killing.
我做了這個來祛除迷魂的藥效
I worked this up to counteract the effects of Vertigo.
給狄格爾注射  我...
Give it to Diggle. I...
我得回法庭去
I need to get back to court.
我不在的時候  盡一切努力
While I'm gone, just work up whatever you can
查清楚狄格爾是如何
and figure out how Diggle got
在不知情的情況下攝入迷魂的
Vertigo in his system without his knowledge.
好  去吧
Ok. Go.
你第一次聽說
When was the first time
那項事業是什么時候
you head about this so-called Undertaking?
跟別人一樣  在我媽開記者招待會的時候
When everyone else did, when my mother gave the press conference.
你好像不是很能接受
Doesn't seem like you took it too well.
我很吃驚
I was surprised.
誰不會吃驚呢
Who wouldn't be?
你母親當時  立刻就被收監了
Uh, your mother was, um, immediately take into custody,
不過你似乎去看守所里看過她
but I assume you went down to the precinct to see her?
其實在她搬走之前我都沒見過她
Um, actually I didn't see her until she was moved.
搬到監獄之前
To the prison.
你還記得你是什么時候去看她的嗎
Do you remember when you visited her?
不記得確切日期了
Uh, not the exact date.
沒關系  我有訪客記錄
It's ok, I have the visitor log here.
十月九日
October ninth.
也就是五個月之后
Five months later.
怎么這么久
Why so long?
我  我
Um, I--I...
你沒事吧
Are you OK?
請回答
An answer, please.
為什么等了五個月才去看你母親
Why did it take you five months to visit your mother?
-法官大人  請讓我  -不
- Your honor, if I-- - No.
我想聽這個問題的答案
I want to hear this.
我需要時間
I needed time.
我那時
I was...
很生氣  可能是太生氣了
Angry. So angry, perhaps,
所以用了五個月你才原諒她
that it took you five months to forgive her?
事情很復雜
It was complicated.
不  很簡單
No. It's very simple.
你因為你母親的所作所為而責怪她
You blamed your mother for what she had done.
那么陪審團為什么不能
So why shouldn't the jury?
法官大人  我們沒有問題
Your honor, we have no further questions
詢問證人了
for the...witness.
亞當
Adam!
在哪呢
Where is it?
東西在哪呢
Come on, where is it?!
短襪在哪呢
The hosen, where is it?
什么
What?
箭頭
The arrowhead.
所有報告都說這些尸體旁邊都有箭頭
Every report said it was with these bodies.
你說你和朋友曾經在這里
You said you and your friends were here.
現在東西呢
Now, where is it?
把他帶出去
Take him outside.
讓他告訴你他的朋友藏在哪里
Make him show you where his friends are hiding.
帶我們去找他們
Take us to them.
我不知道他們在哪里
I don't know where they are!
告訴我  否則你的手就別想要了
Tell me, or you lose your hand.
我們試試別的選擇
Let us suggest another option.
你把人交給我們  我們就不把你們全殺掉
You hand the kid over to us, and we don't kill you all.
你還好嗎
Hey, are you OK?
不用擔心我  我能承受住
Don't worry about me. I can take it.
和看上去一樣糟糕嗎
Was that as bad as it seemed?
西婭的證詞嗎  確實讓我們受挫
Thea's testimony? It was a set-back.
我們本來指望她來
We were counting on her to--
教化我
Humanize me.
坦白的說  是的
Frankly, yes.
現在我們需要試試別的辦法了
And now we're going to have to go another way.
不不  我跟你說過了  我不會出庭作證的
No. No, I told you, I won't testify.
我知道  但你必需出庭
I know you did. But now you have to.
她是對的  母親
She's right, mom.
珍  能先回避一下嗎
Jean, can you give us a minute?
好的
Yeah.
我知道你要說什么
I know what you're going to say.
但如果我作證  那會毀掉我們的家庭
But if I testify, it will destroy our family.
如果你的律師是對的  你沒有其它選擇
And if your lawyer's right, you don't have a choice.
媽  正是那些秘密讓你陷入現在的困境的
Mom, secrets are what put you in this situation.
秘密和謊言
Secrets and lies.
現在是時候
And now it is time
讓秘密大白于天下了
to give the truth its day.
我們不得不提
Now, I don't want us to lose sight
今天的庭審中的另外一個重要事件
of the other major event in court today.
亞當·唐納犯病之前有什么跡象嗎
Was there any indication of Adam Donner being ill?
沒有  唐納先生倒地前
No, there was very little warning before Mr. Donner
幾乎沒有任何跡象
collapsed to the ground.
我與法庭里
I've spoken to several
和我在一起的幾個人談過了
people that were in the courtroom with me...
感覺如何
How are you feeling?
還好
Fine.
你有張讓人討厭的撲克臉  狄格爾
You have a lousy poker face, Diggle.
他服用解毒劑了嗎
Did he take the antidote?
沒起作用  伯爵肯定改變了配方
Didn't work. The count must have futzed with his recipe.
我聽說了庭審時
Heard what happened with Donner
唐納發生的狀況  還有西婭
at the court, and with Thea.
她怎么樣了
How is she?
會好起來的
Going to be fine.
你的撲克臉不比我好看多少  奧利弗
Your poker face isn't much better than mine, Oliver.
-你好  星城  -費利西蒂
- Hello, Starling City. - Felicity!
想我了沒
Miss me?
你們中的很多人注意到了
Many of you have noticed
你們的身體好像不是自己的
that you're not feeling quite like yourselves...
他控制了所有的本地通信基站
He's taken over all the local station feeds.
追蹤他的信號
Track his signal.
就像我們這位優秀的助理地方檢察官
Like our good assistant district attorney here.
你也許能因為他在正在進行的
You might recognize him from his work
莫伊拉·奎恩的庭審中的工作而認出他
in the ongoing Moira Queen trial.
-你好  亞當  -你想要什么
- Hi, Adam. - What do you want?
和你想要的一樣
I want what you want.
讓你能舒服些
For you to feel better.
死去吧你
Go to hell!
我覺得你希望這種痛苦結束
I do think you want the pain to end,
我可以幫你做到
and I can do that...
用迷魂
with Vertigo.
那是你身體所渴求的全部
It's what all of your bodies crave.
幸運的是  解脫的力量就在這里
Fortunately, the power of relief is right here.
你所需要做的就是去你友好的
And all you have to do is go to your friendly
迷魂供應商鄰居那要一點
neighborhood vertigo dealer and request the cure.
供貨上面  包你滿意
Simply supply and demand at work.
跟我說你想要這個
Now, tell me you want this
那它就是你的了
and it's yours.
所有的痛苦就會立刻  消失
All the pain will just...disappear.
說出來
Say it.
說
Say...
你想要它
You want it.
我  我想  我想要它
I-I--want--I want it.
你看  多簡單的解決辦法
You see...A simple solution.
我是迷魂伯爵
I'm count Vertigo,
不是所有毒品都叫迷魂
and I approve this high.
我們現在做什么
What do we do now?
我們找到他
We find him...
然后干掉他
and we shut him down.
他是在哪里直播的
Where did he broadcast from?
他利用尖端科技研究實驗室的衛星進行信號跳轉
He bounced the signal off of S.T.A.R. Lab's satellite.
他能從馬爾科維亞發送傳輸信號
He could have sent that transmission from Markovia.
他想呆在城里
He would want to stay local.
仔細看視頻  有必要的話一幀一幀查
Scrub the footage, frame by frame if you have to.
一定會有些蛛絲馬跡透露出
There's something on here that gives us a clue
他到底在哪
to where he is.
如果他是在全市散播病毒
If he dosed the whole city,
為什么只有一部分人表現出癥狀
why are only some people showing symptoms?
也許感染是有選擇的
Maybe exposure was selective.
伯爵在只有像你和唐納這樣的人
Count contaminated something that only certain people,
能接觸到的物品里做了手腳
like you and Donner, consumed.
一個戲劇性的變化
A most dramatic turn.
為了避免恐慌擴散
City officials are urging calm,
市政當局呼吁市民保持冷靜
hoping to avoid widespread panic.
副市長萊維茨已經
Deputy Mayor Levitz has...
伯爵已經把星城變成了癮君子樂園
The Count has turned Starling into a city of junkies.
關押唐納檢察官的地方有線索嗎
Any leads on where he's holding A.D.A. Donner?
沒有
Hmm, no.
雖然有點不近人情  但我更擔心其他事
As cold as it sounds, I've got other concerns.
勞蕾爾
Laurel?
亞當的庭審筆記很細致
Adam's trial notes are very thorough.
最好是這樣  你現在要做首席律師了
They better be. You're lead counsel now.
斯賓塞小姐  你才是地方檢察官
Ms. Spencer, you're the District Attorney.
是的  不過陪審團了解你
Yes, but you're the one that the Jury knows.
你會做得很好的  勞蕾爾
You'll do fine, Laurel.
我明白
I know.
我想我找到了亞當的王牌
I just found Adam's trump card.
對不起  我不知道你起來了
Sorry, I didn't hear you woke up.
我只想一個人靜靜
I just want to be left alone.
真遺憾你不能一個人靜靜
Well, too bad that's not an option for you.
不過我有其他辦法
But maybe I know something that is.
揍我
Hit me.
什么
What?
你奇怪為什么我以前總在晚上出去
You wonder why I used to go out at night,
和壞家伙們打架斗毆
looking to throw down with bad guys.
一部分原因是為了拯救這座城市
Part of it was to help the city.
另一部分
And the other part
是為了拯救自己
was to help me.
被一幫街頭混混教訓能拯救你
Getting tuned up by street thugs helped you?
是啊  我也不是省油的燈
Yeah, well, I gave as good as I got.
可以了
There we go.
揮拳的時候  我很憤怒
When I would throw a punch, I'd be so angry.
我會感到怒氣在我體內升騰
I'd feel this heat rising inside of me,
喉嚨里  胸口處
in my jaw, in my chest.
還有拳頭
And my fists.
我需要個地方發泄
But I needed somewhere to go.
來
Come on.
西婭  你很生氣
Thea, you're angry.
可能對你母親  地方檢察官  甚至你自己
At your mother, the D.A., yourself, maybe.
如果你不把怒氣釋放出來
But that anger is going to chew up your insides
它會絞碎你的內心
if you don't let it out.
我不會打你的  羅伊
I'm not going to hit you, Roy.
試試
Try.
Try!
我說了揍我  你剛剛那一下
I said hit me, right? 'Cause that felt like--
我根本沒有感覺
that didn't really feel like anything.
好多了  但要繃直手腕
Better. But keep your wrists straight.
不要只靠胳膊
Don't just use your arm.
把全身的力氣集中到一起
Put your entire body into it.
來  再試試
Come on, again.
至少讓我告訴萊拉
At least let me call Lyla.
她除了擔心什么都不能做
All she could do is worry about me.
我有新發現
I found something.
看不出來有什么
I don't see anything.
你要注意看  唐納看到了什么
Because you have to see what Donner does.
他的眼睛上有反光
His eye caught a reflection.
能放大點嗎
Can you enhance?
你問這種問題是在鄙視我嗎
It hurts me that you feel a need to ask.
那是什么  翅膀
What are those, wings?
這是市政印章
It's the city seal.
星城檔案局
Starling Municipal Records Department.
那棟建筑自從辦公電子化后
That building's been abandoned
已經被廢棄
since the city went to digital.
時過境遷
Dollars to donuts,
現在變成了伯爵實施犯罪的地方
that's where the Count is operating out of.
他不會逍遙很久的
Not for long.
你不該來這里
You shouldn't be here.
-我的律師要  -莫伊拉
- My attorney needs... - Moira.
我知道跟你談話可能會被取消執照
I know I could be disbarred for speaking with you,
但這跟工作無關
but this isn't something for lawyers.
是關于你的家庭
This is a family matter.
簡告訴我  她安排你明天出庭
Jean told me she's calling you to the stand tomorrow.
是的
Yes.
你不能出庭作證
You can't testify.
如果你不想讓我出庭  勞蕾爾
Well. The fact that you don't want me to, Laurel,
正說明我應該去
is a good indication that I should.
如果你出庭  我將不得不盤問你
If you take the stand, I'll have to cross examine you,
也不得不盡我所能
and I'll have to do it to the best of my ability.
-是的  我明白  -不  你不明白
- Yes, I understand. - No, I don't think you do.
先不管這對奧利弗和西婭有什么影響
Forget about what this will do to Oliver and Thea.
它會搞砸你的案子
It also could undermine your entire case.
所以  莫伊拉  拜托
So, Moira, please.
求你了
Please.
別逼我這么做
Don't make me use this.
你的一切都命懸一線
Everything is at stake for you.
我不想做那個奪走你一切的人
And I don't want to be the one to take it all away.
快點  拜托
Faster, please.
快  我們有一整座城的顧客
Faster! We have a city full of customers.
一點都不夸張
And I mean this literally.
恐怕我的生產設備對于如此高的需求量
I'm afraid my production apparatus is a little over-taxed
有點力不從心  雖然我能容忍
with the increased demand. I can live with it, though.
這座城市可不一定
I can't say the city can.
快走
Go.
別搗亂  我的小心肝
Be still, my heart.
離他們遠點
Step away from them.
我聽說你現在對殺人有點過敏
Yes, I've heard you've developed an allergy to killing.
-快點  -否則呢
- Do it! - Or what?
你會殺我嗎
You'll kill me?
你真成了不殺戮一族
You're really on the no killing wagon?
真遺憾
Shame.
那你可就失去人生一大樂趣了
Really letting one of life's true pleasures pass you by.
你說過你不想出庭作證
But you said you didn't want to testify.
可是你不得不去
But you have to.
-因為我  -不
- Because of me. - No.
你不得不控制損失
You have to do damage control.
這不是你的錯
None of this is your fault.
我們走到這一步是因為我的所作所為
We're here because of what I did.
現在你們都知道真相了
Now, you both know the truth,
但你們不知道全部真相
but you don't know all of it.
勞蕾爾知道
Laurel does.
她知道什么
What does she have?
你們不應該從法庭上才知道
You shouldn't have to find this out in court.
知道什么
Find out what?
若干年前  很多年前
Years ago-- it was many yes ago...
你們的父親正在搞他的
Your father was engaging in his--
他的出軌行為
his extramarital activities.
我當時心志不堅
And I had a moment of weakness.
我也出軌了
I cheated on him.
跟馬爾科姆·梅林
With Malcolm Merlyn.
不
No.
不  我
No, I--
我問過你這事兒
I asked you about this.
去年
Last year.
你說你們倆之間什么都沒有
You said that there was nothing between you two!
是沒有  甜心  我跟他不是什么婚外情
There wasn't. Sweetheart, it wasn't an affair.
非常短暫  而且已經是很久以前了
It was very brief, and a long time ago.
盡管如此  你還是跟梅林先生保持朋友關系
And despite it, you remained friends with Mr. Merlyn.
事實上  他經常參加你們家的派對
In fact, he frequently attended parties at your home.
馬爾科姆殺害我丈夫之前是他最好的朋友
He was my husband's best friend until Malcolm killed him.
這就是為什么你聲稱
And this is why you claimed to feel
你覺得自己和你孩子
as though you were in fear for your life
遭到生命威脅
and the lives of your children?
我覺得這個理由足夠讓人信服了
Well, I think it's a fairly compelling reason.
去年
Last year,
你的第二任丈夫  沃爾特·斯蒂爾
your second husband, Walter Steel,
被梅林先生綁架了  對嗎
was abducted by Mr. Merlyn, is that correct?
是的  如你所說
Yes. So you are saying.
為什么梅林不殺了沃爾特
Why didn't Merlyn kill Walter,
就像他殺掉你第一任丈夫一樣呢
the same as your first husband?
我說服了馬爾科姆不那么做
I convinced Malcolm not to.
馬爾科姆聽從了你的話
And Malcolm listened to you.
你的朋友饒了沃爾特的命
Your friend spared Walter's life,
你卻想讓陪審團相信
and yet, you'd have this jury believing
你和你的孩子當時有生命危險嗎
that you and your children were in danger?
是的  我擔心
We were. I was afraid--
擔心被抓起來
Afraid of getting caught.
不管我年輕時候犯過什么錯
Despite whatever youthful mistakes I might have made,
馬爾科姆·梅林都是個危險分子
Malcolm Merlyn was a dangerous man.
那是對其他人而言
To other people.
但是真正對莫伊拉·奎恩和她的家人
But the only person who truly posed a danger
造成威脅的人
to Moira Queen and her family
就是莫伊拉·奎恩自己
was Moira Queen.
如果你想打我  那你就打吧
Ok, if you want to attack me, go right ahead.
但你想對我說的每一句話
But you should know that you're not going to say anything
我都對自己說過了
that I haven't already said to myself.
我知道這對你來說很艱難
Whoa. I know that that was difficult for you,
我只想關心一下你是不是還好
and I just want to make sure that you're ok.
不  不
No, no.
我不明白在我剛剛的所作所為之后
I don't understand how you can forgive me
你怎么還能原諒我
after what I just did in there.
換了任何人都不會原諒我
I don't understand how anyone could.
顯然  是你們三個
So, obviously you three
把靈符拿出了山洞
took the hosen out of this cave.
把他抬起來
Lift him up.
我現在知道不是他拿的
Now I know he doesn't have it,
所以就是你們倆其中一個
which means one of you two does.
把它給我  我們來談談交換條件
Give it to me, and we'll discuss an exchange.
我們不知道你在說什么
We don't know what you're talking about.
把奧利弗交給我們
Give us Oliver,
我們就讓你們自己去找
and we'll leave you alone to look for it.
還有人想做蠢事嗎
Anybody else want to be stupid?
好吧  把他帶走
Fine. Take 'em.
給他松綁
Cut him loose.
你要干什么
What are you doing?!
我們不能停下來  他們跟上來了
We have to keep moving, they're following us!
我們知道
We know.
顯然  我們還將繼續關注
Obviously we're continuing to monitor
這些重大事件
both of these major stories
今天  星城因為它們而全市嘩然
in what has become a significant news day here in Starling.
莫伊拉·奎恩承認有婚外情
你能告訴我們關于
What can you tell us about--
奧利弗會被他母親的事情重重包圍
Oliver's going to be pretty wrapped up with his mother.
關于"伯爵"是怎么把"迷魂"
You making any process on how the Count's
弄到人體內的  你搞明白了嗎
getting Vertigo into people's systems?
沒什么進展
Not much.
每個點都是出現戒斷癥狀的人的家
Each dot is the home of somebody with withdrawal symptoms.
看起來很隨機
That seems pretty random.
因為的確很隨機
That's because it's very random.
好吧
Ok.
有沒有可能他們不是在家里中招的
What if people weren't exposed at home,
而是在工作時被下藥的呢
what if they got dosed at work?
你能用他們的工作地點建立聯系嗎
Can you do this by their employment addresses?
我真的要好好想想
I'm really starting to wonder
怎么才能讓你們刮目相看了
what it would take to impress you guys.
是一條路徑  穿過城市
It's a trail. A path through the city.
你去過其中任何地點嗎
Any place you've been?
戴爾街59號  我在那里打的流感疫苗
59th and Dell, that's where I got my flu shot.
你是在這些車上打的疫苗  對嗎
You got your vaccination from one of those trucks, right?
其中一輛流動疫苗車
One of those roving flu trucks?
星城移動醫療
這條路徑
The route.
是流感疫苗車的行動路線
It's a flu vaccination tour.
星城移動醫療派出的疫苗車
A truck sent out by Starling City Mobile Care.
打了一針我就上癮了  這可能嗎
I got addicted after one injection? That can happen?
當然可能  不信試試海洛因
Sure. Try heroin some time.
不要試
Not try...try.
好吧  這車現在在哪里
All right, where's the truck now?
城區  你想怎么辦
Downtown. What do you think?
通知奧利弗嗎
Call Oliver?
不不  他現在家事纏身  我去
No, no, he's busy with his family. I'll go.
不行  不能讓你去
Yeah, no. That's not happening.
我去
I'll go.
費利西蒂  太危險了
Felicity, it's too dangerous.
不會有事的  如果有事  我會叫你的
It could turn out to be nothing. If it's not, I'll call.
...您正在觀看的法庭劇
...courtroom drama you've just witnessed?
貝瑟尼  沒人料到取證結果會是這樣
Bethany, no one expected the turn that testimony took.
莫伊拉·奎恩與馬爾科姆·梅林
A revelation that Moira Queen
曾經的一段戀情曝光
once had an affair with Malcolm Merlyn
成為公訴人盤問的火力點
became the sole focus of the prosecution's cross.
有人嗎
Hello?
有人在家嗎
Anybody home?
"迷魂"  被我逮到啦
Vertigo. Got ya.
有意思
Funny, eh?
你把我的臺詞搶先說了
You took the words right out of my mouth.
西婭
Thea?
今晚就到此為止吧
Can we call it a night?
陪審團表示他們可能能出結果了
Jury just signaled that they could have a verdict.
法官不會讓他們回家的
Judge will not send them home.
他希望能結束這案子
He wants to get this over with.
我也想快點結束這案子啊
Line forms behind me.
這么快就能出結果  恐怕不妙吧
A verdict that quickly is bad, isn't it?
我覺得你倆得做好最壞的打算
I think the two of you should prepare for the worst.
我接個電話
Excuse me.
費利西蒂
Felicity...
奧利弗
Oliver.
你不介意我叫你奧利弗吧
Is it ok if I call you Oliver?
聽到我的聲音覺得很意外吧
Surprised to hear from me, right?
但我比你還意外
Not as surprised as I was.
你看  我發現這位
You see, I find this
長得不太美的金發小妞直闖我的地盤
not unattractive blonde getting all up in my business.
她身上有什么呢
And what does she have on her?
奎恩聯合企業的工作牌
A Queen Consolidated I.D. badge.
我問自己  為什么這個名字這么耳熟呢
Now, I think to myself, why does that name ring a bell?
奧利弗·奎恩
Oliver Queen.
去年他想收買我
He tried to buy off me last year,
隨后我就被兜帽男送進了軟墊病室
just before the hood put me in a padded cell.
也就是  綠箭俠
Ipso facto, Arrow.
你去哪兒
Where are you going?!
我辦公室出了點事
Something's come up at the office.
奧利  陪審團還沒出結果呢
Ollie, the jury!
我必須得走了
I have to go.
時髦花哨的辦公室啊
Pretty swanky offices.
在這兒你可以看到你母親造成的所有破壞
You can see all the destruction that your mom caused from up here.
你想干什么
What do you want?
世界和平和個人滿足
World peace and personal satisfaction.
不過順序倒可以反過來
Though not necessarily in that order.
你給我下藥  把我關進監獄
You poisoned me and put me in a hole.
你不知道為此我有多恨你
You have no idea how much I hated you for that.
結果恨你的還不止我一個
Turns out, someone else hates you, too.
-還有誰  -誰
- Who? - Who?
你發現之后會大吃一驚的
Oh, you're going to be surprised when you find out.
他是個有錢人
He's a man of means.
支持我的新事業好讓我把你引出來
Set me up with my new operation so I could draw you out.
-你想干什么  -殺了你
- To do what? - This.
那你得再努力點
You're going to have to try harder.
去死吧
Done!
過來
Come on! Ahh!
現在我們采用方案二
So now we move on to plan b.
奧利弗  別  別為了我做傻事
Oliver, don't! Not for me!
安靜點好嗎  我在威脅他呢
Quiet, please. I'm threatening.
放下你的弓
Lower your bow.
你要找的人是我
Your problem is with me.
與她無關
It's not with her.
那就把這當做是
Well, then, consider this your penalty
逼我采用方案二的處罰吧
for making me go to plan b in the first place.
沒事了
It's all right.
你安全了
You're safe.
你中彈了
Oh, you were shot.
沒什么大不了
Hey. It's nothing.
有什么消息嗎
Any news?
你去哪兒了
Where have you been?
奎恩企業那兒出了點事
Something... Happened at Queen Consolidated.
一會兒看新聞你就知道了
You will see it on the news later.
現在先別擔心
Just don't worry about it.
如果有結果了你要怎么辦
What would you have done if there'd been a verdict?
西婭  我不知道
Thea... I don't know.
你還好嗎
Are you OK?
陪審團回來了
Hey. Jury's back.
走吧
Come on.
我收到了陪審團出結果的紙條了
I have received a note that the jury has arrived at a verdict.
請公布裁決
Please publish the verdict.
星郡最高法院
In the superior court of Star County
對州檢察院向莫伊拉·奎恩提起的
State versus Moira Queen verdict...
一級陰謀指控的裁決是
on one count of conspiracy in the first degree,
被告無罪
the defendant is found not guilty.
對另外503案件謀殺指控的裁決是
On the 503 counts of murder in the first degree,
被告...
the defendant is found...
無罪
not guilty.
媽媽
Mom.
我太愛你們了
I love you both so much.
令人震驚的結果  莫伊拉·奎恩無罪釋放
A stunning result, as Moira Queen is acquitted of all charges.
莫伊拉·奎恩無罪釋放
就在今天
In a day that's provided
一周以來的沖擊和法律糾紛
a week's worth of shocks and legal twists,
在大多數人看來已經落幕
many had pronounced this case a done deal.
恭喜
Congratulations.
這么說合適嗎
Is that appropriate?
她不該贏這場官司的
She should have lost.
她應該被判有罪
She should have been convicted.
你希望她那樣
Did you want her to be?
我認為她有罪
I expected her to be.
這裁決根本不合理
Verdict doesn't make sense.
但你媽媽肯定很高興吧  難以言喻的高興
Still, your mom must be thrilled. Beyond.
更確切地說是驚嚇
It's more like shock, I think.
他們正在收尾  我想來看看你
They're processing her now. I just wanted to check in on you.
還有你
And you.
我好多了
I'm feeling better.
而且  有了迷魂疫苗
And, with the Vertigo tainted vaccine,
奎恩聯合企業的應用科學部門
Queen Consolidated's applied sciences division
發明了不會上癮的治療方法
was able to formulate a non-addictive treatment.
很好
Good.
我得回家見我的家人
I need to meet my family at home.
你們也回去好好休息吧
So you guys go home, get rest.
晚安
Good night.
奧利弗  我
Oliver. I, uh...
-我想向你道謝  -沒事
- I just wanted to say thank you. - Yeah.
我很抱歉
And I'm sorry.
為什么
For what?
我又惹上了麻煩  你只能殺了他
I got myself into trouble again, and you... killed him.
你又開始了殺戮  我很抱歉
You killed again, and I am sorry that I was the one
因為我  你做出了這樣的艱難抉擇
to put you in a position where you had to make that kind of choice.
費利西蒂
Felicity...
他抓住了你  還企圖傷害你
He had you, and he was going to hurt you.
那個抉擇很容易
There was no choice to make.
你為什么那么做
Why did you do that?!
因為你曾經救過我一命
Because you stopped the captain from killing me.
謝謝你能來
Thank you for coming.
莎朵 他看起來不太好
Shado, he doesn't look too good.
他確實不好  這是誰
He's not. Who's this?
說來話長  他們要找的
It's complicated. That hosen thing
那個護身符還在飛機上
they're looking for is back on the plane.
不  在我這里
No, I've got it.
一面刻著佛教的文字
It has a buddhist inscription on one side.
讓我想起我的父親
It reminded me of my father.
我敢肯定他們不是沖著佛教來的
I'm pretty sure they aren't interested in buddhism.
另一面有什么
What's on the other side?
30-30-175-12
30-30-175-12.
一串數字
Ok, numbers, what...
是坐標
Coordinates.
什么坐標
To what?
一艘二戰期間擱淺在這里
A kairyu-class japanese submarine
海龍級的日本潛水艇
which ran aground here during world war II.
這些人為什么要找一艘70年前的潛水艇
What do these guys want with a 70 year old sub?
潛艇本身并不重要  但上面的東西
The sub isn't important, but what's on it...
能夠拯救人類
It'll save the human race.
能救他嗎
Will it save him?
恭喜你  沒有因為自己的愚蠢而死
Well, you survived your own stupidity, congratulations.
你知道嗎  我還指望你能夠應對
You know... I needed you to deal with any resistance
在島上遇到的抵抗  我得說
that I encountered on the island. I got to say,
你做得并不好
you've done a fairly lousy job of that.
恭喜你
Congratulations.
你升任為新船長了
You're the new captain.
綠箭俠再開殺戒
我安排"伯爵"干掉綠箭俠
I arranged for the count to take out the Arrow,
綠箭俠再開殺戒
結果卻是讓他
And all I accomplish is reigniting
重新開始了殺戮
the vigilante's killing spree.
先生  有進展了
Sir, there's been a development.
塞勒斯兄弟
Brother Cyrus...
你感覺如何
how do you feel?
更強大了
Stronger.
很好
Good.
你已經準備好了
Then you're ready.
奎恩女士  擺脫謀殺罪名的感覺如何
Mrs. Queen, how does it feel to get away with murder?
你出去以后  有輛車等著你
Once you go out back, there's a car waiting for you.
是你殺了自己的第一任丈夫嗎
Did you kill your first husband?
別理他們  繼續走
Just keep going.
很明顯奎恩女士對于陪審團
Obviously Mrs. Queen is overjoyed that the jury
法庭速遞  入口
判定她是迫于威脅感到非常滿意
has ruled that she was acting under terrible duress.
這邊請  奎恩女士
This way, Mrs. Queen.
走高速公路比較快
The freeway will be quicker.
抱歉  奎恩女士
I'm sorry, Mrs. Queen.
有人命令我不要帶你回家
I was instructed not to take you home.
至少暫時不要
Not yet.
這是哪里
Where are we?
我不認識這里
I-I don't know this place.
我把她帶來了  先生
I've got her, sir.
你要干什么
What do you want?
你好  莫伊拉
Hello, Moira.
你不是  你不是已經死了嗎
You were supposed...they said you were dead!
在世上的某些地方  死亡不過是幻覺
There are parts of the world where death is an illusion.
我去過一處
I've been to one.
我學會了完美地偽裝
I learned to be very convincing.
但我回來是因為你需要我的幫助
But I returned because you needed my help.
什么幫助
Help?
你的庭審
With your trial.
難道你覺得陪審團無緣無故
You didn't think that jury acquitted you
就會宣布你無罪嗎
without a little persuasion?
天哪
Dear god.
你想怎么樣  馬爾科姆
What do you want, Malcolm?
我在星城還有勢力
I still have resources in Starling.
人脈
Associates.
在地方檢察官辦公室也有
Including one in the D.A.'s office.
我跟進了唐納先生對你的調查
I followed Mr. Donner's investigation of you with interest.
這么多年你如此輕松地隱瞞我們的事
The ease with which you lied about us for years,
讓我思索你是不是騙了我
it made me wonder whether you lied to me.
我沒有
No. No.
我暗地里做了一個小小的親子測試
It was a matter of a simple surreptitious genetics test
證實了我的懷疑
to confirm my suspicion.
別
Don't.
猜猜我在發現西婭是我女兒時有多高興
Imagine my joy at learning that Thea is my daughter.